numbers don't lie right for me it's just
Revenue at the end of the day if my idea
makes the most money no one's going to
say anything to me I don't know I
thought I was like a personality hire or
something hey everyone it's Ryan
Peterman here with another episode of
the podcast today we have a guest who
went from a new grad at Google all the
way to staff by the age of 28 he did it
very fast he has a lot to say about how
to get promoted in Google's culture and
how to work with your manager but I
think the thing that was most
interesting to me about him was that
he's the first person whoever told me
that he wishes the opportunities for for
promotion to staff came later in his
career and he explains why that's the
case if that sounds interesting to you
let's get into the conversation Ricky
welcome to the Pod so today I want to go
over bit about your career I know you
were at Google pretty much your entire
time so you did an internship at Google
you committed full-time and you went
from Junior all the way to staff in your
20s and I just felt like there's a lot
to learn from that so I want to lay that
all out today yeah I'm super excited to
be here and I hope that this podcast is
very helpful to everyone else can you
walk me through the overall Arc of your
career can you just lay it all out I'm
kind of curious about the compensation
and also how fast you got all the promos
at Google I started as a new grad in
2017 and around then I was making 180k
and I had some sign on bonus and I think
that's pretty normal for a new grad
offer from Google and then after that I
got promoted in a year and a half to
level four or what we call like a
midlevel engineer and at that point my
compensation was around 250k which is
again about average for an L4 and a year
and a half after that I got promoted to
L5 so I made it from 3 to 5 in 3 years
that's very fast I got very lucky very
fortunate with my team on average I
would say it would take maybe like four
or five years to get that done so I did
it you know maybe a year and a half or
two years faster than average so at
level five my compensation was 350k
which is again about average it was a
little bit higher because of my initial
stock Grant and then 3 years after that
I got promoted from 5 to six so from
senior to staff level and at the staff
level my compensation was around 500 or
it currently is around 520 maybe more
but it's around there and again that's
also pretty average I think these
numbers really align with what you see
on levels.fyi so hopefully it's no
surprise to anyone so let's go into the
first one that Junior to uh mid-level
promo you said you did a year and a half
at Google what did you learn along the
way can you tell us more about the
ratings that you got and also a little
bit more about the process maybe we can
start with the ratings yeah Google does
ratings on a six-month cycle so the very
first half I got a me expectation which
is pretty normal for anyone who's only
worked there there for 6 months and then
after that I exceeded expectations and
then after that I got the promo with the
level higher than that I was really
nervous about going for this promotion
just because it was like really ahead of
schedule so I was really unsure at the
time if I was going to get it I
definitely had all the attributes I felt
like for the next level in terms of my
impact and how well I was doing at work
but I just wasn't sure if my tenure
would support that and I was a little
bit worried being docked about that but
luckily my manager was supportive helped
put me up for uh promotion and I ended
up getting it it sound like you knew
about it is it initiated by the employee
or the manager at Google at Google it
should be definitely initiated by the
employee I would say though more than
anything it should be an ongoing
conversation between you and your
manager just making sure expectations
are set of when you plan on going for
promotion what projects you're working
on and what's going to move you to the
next level I was asking my manager hey
do you feel like the these projects that
I'm currently doing are for the next
level and making sure my own
expectations were set making sure the
projects I were doing were indeed for
the next level I see so you were fully
aware that the promo was happening and
you were managing up throughout the
whole process yeah definitely I fully
support managing your manager I think
it's something that you have to do if
you want an accelerated promotion time
line what was it that you you did that
actually made the difference at this
level I think just being able to have
Independence and finish projects on your
own is really the Hallmark of what
people are looking for when you're
getting promoted from 3 to four or
Junior to midlevel that you just don't
need that much handholding you can
unblock yourself on your own is there
anything that you did that helped you
unblock yourself anything you'd
recommend for someone that is Junior to
become more independent on the project I
would say what helped me the most was
just asking a lot of questions I think a
lot of people when they first start
because of imposter syndrome they don't
want to seem dumb and I didn't want to
either but I kept telling myself and I
kept reminding myself hey I'd rather ask
questions and look dumb and learn
something and maybe I'll get fired cuz
people think I'm dumb then to do nothing
not learn anything not ask any questions
and get fired I really try to overcome
my imp passive syndrome with that
mindset and I think that's what helped
me learn a lot from others um because in
general a lot of people are really
willing to help really um wanting you to
succeed and grow grow um so through that
I was able to learn how to do things on
my own and move my projects forward by
asking people questions rather than
asking my manager to figure it out for
me you don't want to ask too quick
because then you don't learn anything
and someone just gives you the answer
yeah but you also don't want to block
for too long cuz you're just going to be
sitting there and not learning anything
and it's not productive especially when
I had interns or people who are new the
industry I feel like you should reach
out if you spend more more than half a
day on something if you spend 4 hours on
something and you make no progress
nothing's going to change you might even
want to reach out sooner than that but
of course you want to give it a good try
before you ask the questions yeah 100%
And I think definitely if you're asking
the same question multiple times then is
maybe a red flag you get stuck after
working a while and you ask the question
that's totally fine it's normal and
expected definitely yeah there there's
got to be this upward trajectory if your
diffs they constantly get tons of
feedback back and that doesn't change
after months of work on the same code
phase something's off there but it it's
totally okay if there's the iterations
are coming down there's a lot of
questions but it's getting better over
time that's that's ideal growth so you
got that promo pretty straightforward
honestly in the industry that promo is
just a matter of turning out code and
just doing it more independently so
makes sense that is like aligns with
what I think as well um let's talk about
the senior promo I think you know on
this promo there's a little bit more
change in your behaviors and it's not
just shipping more code so I want to dig
into that for you what did you feel was
the biggest shift and how you were going
about your work that that helped you get
promoted to senior at Google I think the
biggest shift is probably just taking
more and more ownership and getting to a
point where I could confidently say I
owned a certain scope uh or certain area
and the buzzword is the go-to person for
a scope of area so I was able to get to
that point by really understanding a
portion of the code base and pushing out
a lot of projects that had a lot of
impact in that special
area was that something that you you
explicitly planned like you you maybe
with your manager you thought okay that
area there's not a good owner yet I'm
going to go into that area or how did
you become the go-to person I think I
got pretty lucky on this so I work in
ads and um this go of area that I chose
to invest more time in the ad just
didn't look that pretty and I wanted to
make it better and by making it better
uh I was able to also have a lot of
impact so I just picked kind of the most
interesting um scope of area that I kind
of dipped my toes a little bit into and
I just kept working on it and I
continued to find it interesting um and
slowly became more of an owner uh by
doing more and more projects and taking
my time to explore that
area I think some people in depending on
the team structure they have to compete
for scope or they worry about that so in
your case you you didn't run into
anything like that is that right yes my
team is a little bit special because we
usually pick our own projects of course
you can still have projects handed down
by your manager or your manager can help
you pick projects but I really made an
effort to find my own projects making
sure that they had reasonable impact
because I feel like the best projects
that you can find are the ones you find
yourself um because your manager might
not always always give you a project
that's at the next level so I really
looked for projects that were at the
next level had big impact push my
boundaries and put me outside of my
comfort zone so I had to learn um and
improve my technical skills too one of
the most important parts of getting
promoted is getting some Next Level
scope to actually execute on how did you
know that the things you were looking at
were at the next level how did you find
those was there some tech lead that you
were discussing things with or did you
do it more by yourself I think what I
did is I looked around my team and
looked at how other people might have
gotten promoted to senior and tried to
understand oh this is what exactly a
senior level or lfi project look like
and thinking about how I could create
something or find something of that same
scope or complexity and then after that
I took my ideas to my manager and asked
him for feedback asking him hey do you
feel like this is next level of
complexity do you feel like um this is a
reasonable place that I can push the
boundary on and that's also kind of how
I set myself up for success to get a
promotion really early because a year
before I actually got promoted I went to
my manager and I said hey these are all
the things that I think are interesting
that I'm kind of working on um and
here's a road map for the next year of
what I'm planning on doing do you feel
like this is enough for the next level
so already a year before my promotion I
did my best to set expectations with him
in terms of what I'm doing and if it's
at the next level or not so that was
after so right after you got your your
promo to your to the midlevel you put
together that road map and you showed it
to him is that right so after I got
promoted from 3 to 4 I had about 6
months where I was just like trying out
different projects seeing what was
interesting to me and slowly like
figuring out what might a L5 scope look
like uh and then I put together that
one-year road map by myself and then
showed it to my manager and got my
manager's Buy in got it okay
and so as you were going along and
executing on this road map I mean
inevitably at work like things come up
people might want to give you work that
is not on that road map or I don't know
there's some partner asss that come in
what did you do in that case how did you
handle it when work was not at the next
level but someone was asking you to do
it I think you just have to learn how to
say no obviously if it's a bug that you
caused and someone's bringing it to you
you better fix it cuz you know it's your
bug or like if it's your scope of area
and someone finds a bug you should still
fix it but if it's a whole new project
that someone else wants to take you on
maybe it is like the next level scope
and you do think that is a good project
and you work on it but most of the time
I feel like um people will just kind of
like see who might want a project or
who's interested in a project and you
have to decide for yourself hey is this
at the next next level or not do I have
time for this um and I said no to a lot
of products that I felt like were not at
the next level um sure they might have
impact but they weren't going to help me
grow you have any tips for people say no
cuz I think a lot of people they don't
feel comfortable especially if the
work's coming from their manager what's
the right way to say no without causing
issues if it's someone else giving you
work and you don't want to do it I would
escalate to your manager immediately and
be like hey this person's giving me work
I don't want to do it like I what why
why is it being handed to me and trying
to understand like oh maybe it is just
like a bug that you cause so you do have
to fix it and if it's work given to you
by your manager I think I would just try
to push them and be like hey is this
something I have to do I have my own
projects here that I feel like would
have more impact and also help me grow
more can I just do these projects
instead and I think a manager's job and
this is coming from someone who is a
manager is to find projects that help
you grow and succeed and projects that
you actually want to do because
otherwise people might give you a
project and you're forced to do it
you're just going to do a crappy job on
it so it's better for a manager to find
a project that their reports actually
want to do so hopefully your manager is
not giving you projects that you don't
want to
do makes sense so sounds like you had
pretty good managers throughout this
process seems like they were pretty
receptive to what you were saying yeah I
think I just built up um like very early
on this ability to find my my own
projects and have impact my manager I
felt was not too worried about the
projects I was doing and just trusted
that I'd find my own projects to push on
obviously he still gave me a lot of
feedback to help guide me um and help me
understand oh these type of projects
might be good or bad for me but for the
most part my ideas were bottom up rather
than top down and I think that's one of
the ways that I was able to succeed and
get promoted really quickly that makes
sense you talked about knowing which
ideas are impactful and which ones
aren't how did you develop that skill I
think maybe the first thing you have to
do is figure out what exactly impact
means within your org for me I was an
ads so it just meant like how much money
is this going to make does this actually
help the user help the advertiser help
the publisher but if you were on a
different team maybe it's like
increasing the number of daily active
users or interactions with a certain
product so really thinking about what
exactly that impact number meant so
again for me it was revenue and I was
able to find projects by running a lot
of experiments to figure out oh here
there's a gap where I can probably have
a lot of impact and drive a lot of
Revenue here's another Gap that I found
where I can probably drive a lot of
Revenue here too and I think the best
part about this is that numbers don't
lie right for me it's just Revenue other
people might have ideas but at the end
of the day if my idea makes the most
money no one's going to say anything to
me yeah yeah for sure there are metrics
and there are our projects with
well-known Milestones that the whole org
knows is valuable so when you move those
metrics obviously revenue and ads yeah
that there no one can argue if you have
the biggest metric movement let's say
you're a junior engineer that moves it
more than the whole team like okay
obviously that's going to be something
something huge okay so when it actually
got to the the senior promo what what
was that like I would say that from 3 to
four it was a little bit scary but then
from four to five it was even scarier
cuz I knew I was really going against
the grain like I was getting promoted
really fast it's a really expedited
timeline I heard that like the average
time that it takes to get promoted can
be like 2.5 years 3 years 3.5 years so
doing that 1.5 years was really really
aggressive and I was just worried that
um I'd be docked points for not showing
that I was performing at the next level
for an extended amount of time so I knew
it was a pretty big stretch um luckily
my manager still supported me and said
that we can go can go for promotion
though you know like he set my
expectations he was like I'm not sure
like we'll really have to see again you
might be docked but you know let's just
try to go for it and see what happens so
I did end up going for it I was able to
make it it was a really big surprise to
me very fortunate that my manager
supported me even though it was a very
aggressive timeline you one last last
thing on this level is for senior promo
you need to lead a bit more than in the
past levels is there anything that you
did that some people there's like
growing pains to like becoming like a
leader on your team like how was that
experience for you did you have impostor
syndrome at any point it definitely was
a little bit scary and as you said
Growing Pains it takes some time to get
used to almost being confident in
yourself for example like I had some
project ideas that I ultimately handed
off to more Junior Engineers but I was
pretty anxious that they wouldn't pan
out or that the experiments that I gave
them wouldn't do so well and honestly
some of them didn't but I think my
batting average was still higher than
than most people and that definitely
helped but you definitely have to get
used to Leading and just being
comfortable mentoring people and I think
in in buzzwords you would say you'd have
influence on others in their projects
let's go into the staff promo you know I
think it's natural for promos to take
longer later in your career did you feel
stuck at any point honestly I wish I
could have stayed at the senior level a
little bit longer um I feel like being a
senior engineer you of course don't make
as much as if you're a staff or higher
level engineer but you have great work
live balance like I really miss taking a
nap at like 2:00 p.m. or going to the
gym at 3:00 p.m. when there's no one
there um and I think as as you become
more senior you're just involved in lot
a lot of bigger projects that require
more meetings and your structure the
structure of your schedule just becomes
more and more rigid so I think for
people that do want to go to staff
really think about is this something you
actually want like looking at how other
staff Engineers are on your team or on
adjacent teams and looking at what they
are doing and at Google do they have a
up or out policy so you can stay at
senior as long as you want is that right
yes I think maybe you can even stay at
midlevel as long as you want but I'm not
100% sure there's no expectation for
people to go to staff I think becoming a
staff engineer is very much a choice um
that to you know go past Senor go to
staff uh because it is a lot more
responsibility and a lot more work um
and I think some people just don't want
to make that tradeoff if you were to
take you at the senior level versus you
at the staff level what's the biggest
difference in your mind I feel like at
level five or as I as a senior I
definitely started owning a space I had
a scope that I was like well versed in
and I did a lot of projects and had
impact there and I think what helped me
go from senior to staff is now that I
really knew a scope of area how can I
push the boundaries of that scope of
area challenge the status quo and have a
larger influence over that scope of area
I think I got a lot of points for
leading and pushing the boundary of that
area and through that I was able to have
a lot of impact and just like being a
leader in that space rather than someone
that just knows the space I see so you
were creating scope and influencing
across teams yeah definitely just like
both cross functionally across org like
it involved a lot of um at some points
like very high leadership Buy in so I
think once you start being the one to
kind of like make those decisions and
like push those decisions up I think
that starts to show very clearly staff
level influence one of the things to
getting a staff is that you need to find
that staff level project and in a lot of
cases the manager can't just hand that
to you that's something you need to find
yourself how did you find your anchor
project that got you promoted to staff I
think what helped me find my staff
project is just working in a space and
then being like why why are we doing
things this way this doesn't make sense
to me and then starting to challenge you
know how we've been doing things for a
while so there's definitely a status quo
and uh like one specific example is we
had a lot of support backed by user
research that showed you know this one
thing to be true but then when we
actually ran the experiments it
conflicted with user research and I was
able to push that and show that you know
despite what user research shows we can
do this instead to have a lot of impact
so I would say what really helped me
have that staff level project is knowing
a space so well that it can start to
challenge the boundaries or the rules
that may have been set up and pushing it
towards almost like this new frontier
for a specific scope and I think we
talked a little bit about influence and
how important it is for staff how do you
usually go about influencing other
people I think at work I just kind of
already established a brand of being
someone who was able to find imp ful
projects or just find impact in general
and then I would kind of pitch my ideas
to other people um you know obviously
not trying to step on anyone's toes but
just giving ideas and collaborating with
others and I think a lot of people
trusted my ideas at that point and they
also panned out really well fortunately
so I think that's how I kind of
established influence with other teams
or cross functional Partners just
building a relationship ship um
cross-pollinating ideas with other
people and ultimately getting those uh
ideas to become projects and ultimately
succeed in launch you had been at the
company for a while and you had already
evidence of past results that gave you
credibility and so that made it that it
made it so that you could influence
people a lot more easily is that right
yeah I would definitely say so if your
projects keep flunking then you know
people might not be as willing to try
out your projects or trust your word as
much that makes sense I think that's one
thing that is unique about your career
compared to a lot of our friends is that
you have been at Google since we
graduated you've been in the same Org
the entire time so all those people know
you they've seen you as this rising star
that has been having a lot of success on
all these projects and so it's just
natural that you're probably going to be
more influential than if you got hired
at the senior level on this team you
have to build all of that credibility
from scratch yeah I don't want to say
rising star but I definitely you know
had some successful projects that I
think were able to Showcase that you
know my my word had some value or some
truth behind
it yeah yeah yeah the rising star mile
just like that you've had past success
you've had past
success you're believable you're
credible exactly they see your name and
they're like okay this Project's
probably be a good idea for the staff
level like you also like you were tlm
for some time as well can you talk a
little bit about you know why did you
want to try Management in the first
place I think that's like a common thing
that everyone's thinking is IC they want
to make that decision for themselves at
some point so how did you make that
decision why did you want to try and
manage I wanted to try and management
just cuz I think I already had a lot of
fulfillment in helping people grow
finding projects even though I wasn't
directly managing people there are
definitely mentees I had at work I also
mentored interns at times and it was
just a really fun time watching them
succeed and you know it's almost like
having a kid and watching them grow and
I really enjoyed that so that's timately
why I wanted to try out being a manager
luckily my team was also very supportive
of that idea and I started managing
around two years ago that makes sense
did your manager really vet your
motivations for wanting to become a
manager before you you became one how
did that process go I don't know
honestly um my I I I pitched idea to my
manager I think even once I was at the
senior level for a while I think I kind
of said hey like eventually one day I'd
like to become a
manager um and I think just the right
opportunity came up I do feel like
becoming a manager really early on was a
little bit awkward just
because I some at times felt like I
wasn't mature enough to be a manager
when you say not mature enough what does
that mean I think I felt a little bit
awkward at times uh one example is like
being in a meeting of a bunch of
managers and I think a lot of the
managers in our or skewed to be a little
a little bit older just you know
naturally cuz some of them were even
like higher level managers and have been
managers for a while um so there's it
felt a little bit awkward there another
time it felt awkward is like when I'm
out at a music festival and I'm really
drunk and then I see my reports out
there I think at the end of the day it's
probably fine but I think uh I just
didn't really think that that would
happen until actually happened that
makes sense and you know before you came
had you done um interns or any uh you
did you have any management experience
or did you just kind of ask your manager
and he was like okay maybe one day and
it just happened yeah I did not have
like any special managing experience I
never had an intern I was a little bit
surprised for some reason I thought that
there'd be more of like a textbook on
how to be a great manager but I feel
like a lot of people just kind of get
thrown in and then uh um you know they
do their best U not saying that Google
doesn't have resources Google has tons
of resources
but I don't know I thought there'd be a
little bit more structure but it seems
like in general people just become a
manager when you became manager what do
you feel was the biggest difference
between uh being an IC and and manager I
think what a lot of people told me
before I became a manager um and I agree
with their advice even today is that
when you're just like a TL you have all
the fun Parts you get to help them grow
you get to help them succeed and then
all the harder Parts is like giving
difficult feedback when people are not
performing so well and a lot of almost
the busy work of writing reviews and
like going to calibration sessions so
there's just a lot more I guess overhead
when you're a manager as opposed to to
being an IC but I do feel like at the
same time it's a little bit more
rewarding when you actually get to see
your reports get promoted because you
are their manager right you help them
get promoted as opposed to just being a
TL and helping someone get
promoted definitely so now that you've
tried it do you think that you regret
becoming a manager I would say that I
just wish I became a manager later I
think at the time my team just we had
like a really odd scenario where we had
20 new hires and I felt like I was
helping them all and I wanted a more
formal role um just so that I would only
be responsible for the people that
actually managed which was four people
rather than 20 people so in that sense
like I feel like I was able to have more
time um back because I only had to
really help four
people but if I had the choice I
probably would have been a senior
engineer maybe a couple more years just
because I think there are less
responsibility and it's less stress and
I think in your I don't know early or
mid 20s when you want to just relax a
little bit more it's just better to be a
senior engineer than to be a staff level
engineer or
higher that's fair yeah and this there's
a lot more meetings at the staff level
especially as a manager I feel like it's
it's all meetings and sometimes yeah
it's definitely a skill that I feel like
you have to learn or get used to just
powering through 6 hours of 8 hours of
backtack meetings or one-on ones some
managers I think have all of their
meetings in one day some of them have it
like sprinkled out throughout the week
but in general as you become more senior
whether or not you are a manager or not
a manager at the levels of 6 7 8 you're
going to have a lot of meetings no
matter what because the influence you
have is always going to be through other
people and it's going to be less code
that you actually write yourself whether
or not you're an IC or a manager so for
me at least I think when I first
graduated from college I was like oh my
God I want to be a director one day it's
going to be so fun but I think as I
become closer and closer to these high
levels I'm understanding what it
actually means and it means no more
random naps at 2: or 3: p.m. whenever I
want it means no going to the gym at you
know 11:00 a.m. obvious obiously to a
certain extent you can still have doctor
appointments in the middle of day if you
have to but there's definitely less
flexibility and I think if you look at
the calendars at work of any of these
more senior people you'll also see sure
they still only work 9 to5 but they are
working 9 to5 they are definitely
working I feel that it's there's
definitely a lot more meetings I think
when I when I got promoted to staff I
remember my schedule was basically a
large chunk meetings 9 to 5 not not
entirely 9 to but meetings kind of just
like fragment your focus time yeah so
then every day I would have you know
fragmented meetings for most of 9: to 5
and then I would start working on my
stuff at 5: until like I went to bed so
yeah I totally agree it's it's can can
become a lot yeah um so I guess last
thing you actually go for the promo of
course were there any differences
between the past promos or was it pretty
straightforward forward I already said
that I was unsure from 3 to 4 and 4 to 5
I was also very unsure from 5 to 6
honestly uh I definitely had really good
ratings so that was definitely a signal
like I had like you know the highest
ratings possible uh for a while already
but I was kind of just unsure just
because I think people have said that
going from 5 to six is notoriously hard
three to four four to five obviously it
still takes work but it's a little bit
more straightforward and people say that
going from five to six is almost like a
complete job change in some aspects so I
was pretty worried about it just cuz
even if you're a superstar senior
engineer and you're having tons of
impact it doesn't necessarily mean that
you are going to be a great staff
engineer though I did end up going for a
promo again I feel very fortunate very
lucky that my manager was supportive and
I was able to get promoted and only took
me one try which is I'm also pretty
thankful for to all of your promos there
was never a a miss and try again miss
and try again it just landed every time
yes but wow I was very lucky I was very
lucky forunate yeah looking at the whole
career you think you could do it again
or was a large part of this luck I think
you definitely have to be a little bit
lucky just cuz sometimes you might not
enjoy the team that you're on or maybe
your manager is just out on fraternity
or maternity leave so they can't help
you as much or they can't support your
promotion as well I think where I got
lucky was that my team was a product
area that I ended up really liking even
though I didn't pick that I didn't pick
my team but they just matched me there
and I've been on that team for 7 years
now clearly I like it to some capacity
and I think my team was also relatively
stable my manager although I had some
like manager shifts ultimately it was
still under the same broader and larger
team so nothing crazy in terms of reorgs
or restructuring that might have
hindered my career progress but I will
say that luck is like two parts one of
them is the chance of an opportunity
actually coming along right sometimes
you just have to wait for that and it
might take longer it might not take as
long I think the second part is being
prepared for when that chance actually
comes so just making sure that you're
doing your best and doing the right
thing so that when an opportunity does
come along you can actually take
advantage and seize the opportunity what
percent of your career do you think has
been due to your abilities and what
percent do you think was luck um I would
say maybe like half half uh
um like I'm pretty confident that
eventually I would get to senior and I
think that most people will eventually
get the senior as long as they're like
making sure to grow and putting work in
but maybe if I was on a different team
or I just really did not like the stuff
I was working on it might have taken me
longer cuz i' have to switch teams and
then get ramped up in their code stack
so I think I was just really fortunate
that uh things worked out the way they
did but I definitely made sure to put in
the effort and was very conscious about
the next level and what I had to do to
get there that makes sense yeah luck is
a huge part of it there could be an
engineer that's better than you but
they're I don't know the team they're on
is like literally just the worst it's
reorg every 6 months they have no
consistent project and so in that case
of course you couldn't do it and on flip
side it sounds like you had a lot of
things around it like a good manager and
like the scope to continue to grow your
product was like impactful and all of
that so um that makes sense um one of
the last things I want to talk about is
um you know I think we kind of mentioned
that out of all of our friends I think
it's a little bit unusual to be at the
same company for seven years um
especially in this industry people are
kind of job popping to try out new
things or you know get more compensation
or whatever um and so
what kept you at Google for so long yeah
I think it's really important to ask
yourself I don't know maybe every 3
months just ask yourself hey am I still
enjoying the work I'm working on do I
still feel like this team has whatever I
want for me it was like I really wanted
some career growth I also really wanted
to travel a lot I didn't care as much
about what I was working on as long as
it wasn't like too boring so my team I
felt always had those opportunities for
me and that's why why I didn't leave but
I think what I often tell people is I
just kept asking myself is the grass
greener here or elsewhere and it was
greener on my side of the lawn so I
ended up staying that doesn't mean that
I wasn't thinking about leaving or if I
should change teams every so often to
make sure that the job was doing as much
it was for me of course there's
survivorship bias right I'm sure people
that did not get promoted as quickly
maybe they just didn't really enjoy the
team where didn't enjoy the work whereas
I just had a good match up that makes
sense yeah and think there's pros and
cons to staying at the same team there's
this momentum that you get by staying on
the same team and the same company
you're like this snowball of of of
organizational context and like the
code-based knooow and after four years
in the same area you're not just the
go-to person in one area you're like
go-to person in like many areas and you
just become this uh person that just
knows how to do get everything done you
have all the relationships so it if you
can get lucky with a good um you know or
setup and all of that there is this this
uh benefit to to having all that context
that can give you unusually fast career
growth you know on the flip side of
course you can job hop and try to get
promos too so that it's not uh black and
white one is better than the other I
guess it's like a Counterpoint to I feel
like the the common opinion is like you
should jump and you should switch and
there is actually some value to thing as
long as your Situation's good yeah okay
and the last thing I want to know is if
you were to talk to that that Ricky at
the beginning of your career Junior
engineer Ricky just end the industry
what advice would you give yourself and
and
why I think to my younger self I would
just tell him to trust himself a little
bit more cuz I think for for a very long
time I just had so much impost syndrome
I was so anxious that um you know I
wasn't going to do so well and over time
I like built up that confidence like
through projects my projects succeeding
and working well with others and getting
good feedback but I think I was like
really unsure of myself and I actually
feel like I could have done more if I
was willing to trust my judgment a
little bit more or have more of almost
like audacity to um P the boundary and
try new things um because I had a lot of
ideas that I felt like I maybe waited a
little bit too long because you know I
felt like oh am I going to rock the boat
too much but um I ended up doing a lot
of those projects that did rock the boat
and they were very successful and I wish
I just you know trusted myself a little
bit more to do it earlier so I'd be less
anxious and stressed all the time and be
Fring less over imposter syndrome in the
beginning of my career when you say say
imposter syndrome was that mostly about
your technical skills or is something
you learned that made you have less
imposter syndrome I don't know I thought
I was like a personality higher or
something uh uh and over time I realized
you know obviously like Google's not
going to do that but I think I was
always just a little bit worried cuz I
think during my interviews too for
Google I think I like did okay I don't
feel like I like hit a home run and the
same thing with my internship I didn't
feel like I hit a home run and also
think at the lower levels I wasn't
really sure how to kind of gauge my
performance and even though I would like
bother my manager a lot and be like am I
doing okay like are things going well
and he'd tell me like oh yeah you're
doing fine you know I would still like
kind of be anxious like oh but like is
it enough um is it just okay or is it
like am I doing like
am I passing is this like a c that I'm
doing am I like doing an A+ like what's
the vibe you know I was just stressing
out about
that yeah that makes sense that's that's
Supernatural um awesome all right well
yeah I think that's everything Ricky is
there anything that you want to plug or
you know where can the audience find you
yeah so on social media I'm finding
Ricky if you want to watch my content
it's not really Tech related I have to
warn you I feel like I'm in a very
different Niche than uh Ryan here but uh
if you do want to follow me or check out
my socials it's finding Ricky um and I
hope that this podcast was helpful to
everyone and I'm so happy that I could
be here today awesome all right thanks
so much for your time Ricky all right
thanks everyone bye hey Ryan here thanks
so much for listening to the podcast I
hope that it was helpful and if you want
to hear more from Ricky you can go and
check him out on YouTube at finding
Ricky he recently
posted a video about a day in the life
in as a staff engineer at Google I know
it sounds Sensational but actually I
think he did a good job in capturing
what the day-to-day is like it's not
just flexing big Tech perks it's more
about the daily work of a staff engineer
and how things kind of become much more
different as you have more and more
responsibility so you can take a look at
that and then two other things that I
want to add is one thank you so much for
the feedback on the first video I hope
that you can see that I took it to heart
and the production quality is a little
bit better still has a long way to go
but look at the background here I bought
a backdrop to make it a a little bit
nicer and I'll be using that for future
videos and then the other thing too that
I got a lot of feedback on is the jump
cuts and so I tried to get rid of as
many of those as possible while still
removing filler words and things like
that so you can see that I'm playing
with the camera angles I really
appreciate the feedback and if you have
any more feel free to drop comments on
YouTube I will take a look there and try
to make then every episode incorporate
the feedback that I get thanks so much
for your time